ricoh-usa.com 2006-06-15

# Ricoh-USA - Privacy Policy

RICOH recognizes the importance of personal Data. Therefore, RICOH exerts its best efforts to pay attention to protection of your privacy on The RICOH Web Site and strongly adheres to the following policies. 

**Privacy statement Version 1.1 - December 2002**

Ricoh is committed to protecting your privacy and to technology that gives you the most powerful and secure online experience with the Ricoh Corporation Web Site (the "site"). You can travel through most of the Site without giving us any information about yourself. But sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request. This policy outlines our personal information handling practices. If you give us personal information, we will treat it according to this policy. 

Our policy regarding the safeguard of your information when collected is consistent with the five privacy principles of Fair Information Practices and the U.S. - E.U. Safe Harbor standards. 

**Principles: Awareness, Choice, Accuracy and Access, Security and oversight (Enforcement).**

**Awareness**

Ricoh publishes an Online Privacy Statement to make you aware of our privacy policy, practices and of the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. 

**Choice**

Once you have chosen to provide Ricoh with personal information, meaning any information that may be used to identify an individual, including, but not limited to, a first and last name, email address, a home, postal or other physical address, other contact information, title, birth date, gender, occupation, industry, personal interests, other information when needed to provide a service you requested, Ricoh will maintain that information. 

Ricoh will not sell, rent, or lease your information to others. Unless we have your permission or are required to do so by law, we will only share the personal data you provide with other Ricoh entities and/or business partners who act on our behalf for the uses described in "how we use it". These other entities and/or suppliers, may include those in the United States and/or any other countries, and are bound by the appropriate confidentiality and data protection agreements. 

**Accuracy & Access**

In certain areas of the Site access is limited and requires the use of a password or may require you to provide personal data. In those areas, Ricoh makes every effort to keep your personal information accurate and up to date. To protect your privacy and security, we may take reasonable steps to verify your information by using that information to contact you. Allow you access to your information via a web page, so that you may view, update or correct your information. We will provide you a set of instructions on that web page and also allow you to opt-out of the agreement, contract, provide your name, email and/or address and relevant information about subscriptions or registrations you may have with Ricoh. This opt-out function will also enable you to cancel all marketing and support communications and newsletters, including software driver subscriptions. 

**Security**

Ricoh is committed to ensuring the security of your information. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. As part of real-time payment processing, Ricoh uses 128 bit encryption and SSL (Secure Socket Layer) certificates when collecting or transferring sensitive data such as credit card information. The service gives you an extra level of protection to guard against credit card fraud. This secure data transfer and validation process ensures the highest level of security available. You are invited to visit the area outlined "data security" to learn more. 

**Oversight**

If you have comments or questions about our privacy policy, please complete the web form, and select "Privacy" as your subject category. To help us process your request, please include all relevant contact information, name of the program(s) and action requested. 

**What we collect**

On some of Ricoh's web sites, you can order products or services, make requests, and register to receive materials. The types of personal information collected on these pages are name, contact and billing information, transaction, and credit card information. We may also ask you to provide information as to your personal or professional interests, demographics, experience with our products, and more detailed contact preferences. This information allows us to better serve your needs and to maximize product improvement possibilities and our customer service efforts. 

**How we use it**

Ricoh uses your information to better understand your needs and provide you with better service. Specifically, we use your information to help you complete a transaction, to communicate back to you, to update you on services and benefits, and also on occasion personalize our web pages for you. Credit card numbers are used solely for payment processing, fraud protection, and are not retained for other purposes. 

From time to time, we may also use this information to contact you for market research or to provide you with marketing information we think would be of particular interest. At a minimum, we will always give you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving such direct marketing or market research contact. We will also follow the "laws of the State of New Jersey" requirements, such as allowing you to opt-in before receiving unsolicited contact, where applicable. Some of our web pages also use cookies and other technologies for data analysis. To learn more about these please see our section outlined, "How we use cookies." 

**Who we share it with**

Ricoh will not sell, rent, or lease your personal information to others. Unless we have your permission or are required to do so by law, we will only share the personal data you provide online with other Ricoh entities and/or business partners who act on our behalf. These entities and/or suppliers, may include those in the United States and/or any other countries, are governed by our privacy policies with respect to the use of States and/or any other countries, are governed by our privacy policies with respect to the use of this data and are bound by the appropriate confidentiality and data protection agreements. In addition data collected online may also be combined with information you provide when you register your ownership of products or service. 

**How to use cookies**

A cookie is a small data file that certain web sites write to your hard drive when you visit them. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID that the site uses to track the pages you've visited, but the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can't read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Some parts of Ricoh's website uses cookies to track user traffic patterns. We do this in order to determine the usefulness of our website information to our users and to see how effective our navigational structure is in helping users reach that information. If you prefer not to receive cookies while browsing our website, you can set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies and refuse the cookie when your browser alerts you to its presence. You can also refuse all cookies by turning them off in your browser, although you may not be able to take full advantage of the Ricoh website if you do so. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use/navigate through many parts of our website, except where access to areas to web pages which require a login and password. 

**Acceptance of Terms**

The services that Ricoh provides to you are subject to "Terms of Use". Ricoh reserves the right to update these terms at any time without notice to you. The most current version of these terms can be reviewed by clicking on the "Terms of Use" hypertext link located at the bottom of our web pages. 

**Description of Services**

Through its network of web sites, Ricoh provides you with access to a variety of resources, including developer tools, download areas, communication forums and product information (collectively "Services"). These Services, including any updates, enhancements, new features, and/or the addition of any new web sites, are subject to the "Terms of Use". 

**Personal and non-commercial use limitation.**

Unless otherwise specified, the Ricoh Corporation web sites are for your personal and non-commercial use. You may not modify, copy, distribute, transmit, display, perform, reproduce, publish, license, create derivative works from, transfer, or sell any information, software, products or services obtained from the sites. 

**Children and Privacy**

The Site does not knowingly solicit personal information from children. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that we have personal information on a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information from our systems. 

Ricoh encourages parents to go online with their kids. Here are a few tips to help make a child's online experience safer: 

  * Teach kids never to give personal information, unless supervised by a parent or responsible adult. Includes name, address, phone, school, etc. 
  * Know the sites your kids are visiting and which sites are appropriate. 
  * Look for Web site privacy policies. Know how your child's information is treated.

Check out the FTC's site(1) for more tips on protecting children's privacy online. 

**Linked Web Sites**

Links to third party web sites from our pages are provided solely as a convenience to you. If you use these links, you will leave the Ricoh web site. RICOH HAS NOT REVIEWED ALL OF THESE THIRD PARTY SITES AND DOES NOT CONTROL NOR IS RESPONSIBLE FOR ANY OF THESE SITES, THEIR CONTENT OR THEIR PRIVACY POLICY. RICOH DOES NOT ENDORSE OR MAKE REPRESENTATIONS ABOUT THEM, OR ANY INFORMATION, SOFTWARE OR OTHER PRODUCTS OR MATERIALS FOUND THERE, OR ANY RESULTS THAT MAY BE OBTAINED FROM USING THEM. IF YOU DECIDE TO ACCESS ANY OF THE THIRD PARTY SITES LINKED FROM THE SITE, YOU DO SO AT YOUR OWN RISK. 

**Data Security**

Ricoh safeguards the security of that data you send us with physical, electronic, and managerial procedures. In certain areas of our websites, Ricoh uses industry-standard 128-bit SSL-encryption in conjunction with firewalls to enhance the security of data transmissions. While we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure the security of the information while it is in transit to us, and so we urge you to take every precaution to protect your personal data when you are on the Internet. We also suggest that you update your browser to the most current software/updates available, change your passwords often, use a combination of letters and numbers, and after transactions close your browser to ensure that no data can be collected once you leave our site.
